你还在看吗
You're still on that thing?
你一直盯着电脑到底看什么呢
What are you constantly looking at on your computer?
你真的想要
Is that a question
家里的人开始问这个问题吗
you really want people asking around here?
说得对 我不想
Indeed, it is not.
我只是在看大学录取情况
I'm just checking college acceptances.
学校随时可能发通知
I mean, they should be posting them any day.
你不能把整个春假
You cannot spend your entire spring break
花在等录取通知上吧
worrying about college admissions.
你应该跟海莉一起去那个音乐节
You should go to that -- that music festival thing with Haley.
找点乐子 学会放松
Do something fun. Learn to relax a --
我们所有的遥控器都得留着吗
Do we have to keep every remote we have ever owned?
垃圾填埋场的某处刚有个光驱弹了出来
Somewhere in a landfill, a laser disc just ejected.
我不能带艾丽克斯去音乐节
Uh, I can't bring Alex to the festival
因为我是去工作 勘查最新流行趋势
because I am going for work to research new fashion trends.
我得和人们打成一片
I need to blend in, you know?
所有人都会以为她是条子
Everyone will think she's a cop.
我可以坐在这担惊受怕毁掉自己的一天
Well, I could sit here and worry and ruin my day,
或者跟海莉一起去毁掉她的一天
or I could go with Haley and ruin hers.
我去拿我的防晒霜
I'll grab my sunscreen.
早上好
Good morning.
爸
Hey, Dad.
我不想让你难堪 可海莉起得比你早
I hate to shame you, but Haley woke up before you.
海莉昨天没跑十公里
Well, Haley didn't run a 10K yesterday
去为秃头症患者争取关注
to raise awareness for alopecia.
秃头症是什么
What's alopecia?
这就是我去跑步的原因
That is why I run.
亲爱的 今天的春季大扫除
Honey, I could really use your help
真的需要你的帮助
with spring cleaning today.
我需要把这些盒子都拿到捐赠中心去
I got to get all these boxes down to the donation center.
我想帮 可是我要工作
Wish I could, but I've got work.
然后还要和卢克一起跳蹦床
Then Luke and I have got some important trampolining to do.
我真喜欢这么平等的分工方式
I just love how equally we divide our responsibilities.
鉴于你的学校活动取消了
Figured we'd do a little father/son bonding
我们该做点父子活动
since your school trip was canceled.
你可以教我邓菲翻转
You can teach me the Dunphy Tuck.
我欣赏你的热情 但那太危险了
I love your enthusiasm, son, but it's way too dangerous.
一个动作错了 你就可能摔个嘴啃弹簧
One wrong move, and you're eating springs.
不 那不是
Oh, no, no, those are --
那是我的班卓琴吗
Is that my banjo?
当我遇见身边这位女士的时候
When I met this little lady sitting next to me,
我们一见钟情
it was love at first sight.
是的 我已经弹棉花
Yep, I've been noodling around on the ol' flyswatter
弹了好几年了
for a couple of years now.
被伟大前辈们所激励
I was inspired by the greats
斯克鲁日 科米特
-- Scruggs, Kermit.
尽管这玩意练起来很难
It's hard to practice, though,
因为它会让克莱尔欲火焚身
because it gets Claire so hot and bothered.
我觉得我听够了
- What do you -- - I think I've heard enough.
你真走运
Lucky for you,
我刚好有时间弹一曲《小短面包》
I've got time for a couple verses of "Shortnin' bread."
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
不 它在盒子里 要被丢掉了
No, no, it's in the box. It's leaving the house.
我再也忍受不了那鬼哭狼嚎了
I-I can never hear that awful thing again.
-可你还叫我班卓琴手呢 -我知道
- But you called me "Banjovi." - I know.
只要能让它停下 我做什么都可以
I did whatever was necessary to make it stop.
等等 那是说你也不喜欢我吹风笛吗
Wait. Does that mean you also didn't like my bagpiping?
所以我们才有了卢克吗
Is that why we have Luke?!
不是这样的
It's not.
是这样吗
Is it?
小卡 你不吃甜品吗
Ay, Cam, no dessert for you?
不吃
No, none for me.
今晚我要穿上紧身猫猫装
I have to fit into a skintight cat costume tonight
因为要去...
because I'm gonna --
你们关上房门做任何事
Whatever you do behind closed doors
都是你们自己的事
is your own business.
因为我要在教职员才艺秀上演唱《回忆》
Because I'm singing "Memory" at the faculty follies.
为了筹集资金
It's a fundraiser
教师们要表演节目
where the teachers do a little talent show.
要不我去看你演出吧
Ay, maybe I come see you.
我戒掉了肥皂剧
I need to find something to watch
总得找点东西看
since I had to give up my soap operas.
因为你一心看剧忽略了乔吗
Oh, because you've been neglecting Joe?
不 因为我让杰戒了雪茄
No, it's because I asked Jay to stop smoking cigars,
他说如果我能戒肥皂剧
and he said that he would quit
他就戒雪茄
if I stopped watching the soap operas.
可那太难了
But it's very hard.
有什么难的
What's so damn hard?
每周播的都是一样的
It's the same thing every week --
健忘症 邪恶的双胞胎
Amnesia, evil twins,
最后两个女人在喷泉里打架
two ladies end up fighting in a fountain.
有什么好看的 是为了逃脱现实吗
I mean, what is it? Is it some sort of an escape?
至少比朝宝宝脸上吐烟好
It's better than blowing smoke in our baby's face.
说到这个 他去哪儿了
Where did he go, anyways?
莉莉的女童军营发来了邮件
Oh, there's an e-mail from Lily's scout camp.
-希望一切都好 -她很好
- I hope everything's okay. - She's fine.
米奇尔很担心 因为他不喜欢露营
Mitchell's nervous because he's not a camper.
他觉得住的酒店没有电视剧频道
His idea of roughing it is a hotel stay
就算条件艰苦了
where the cable doesn't get Bravo.
登记入住时酒店应该告诉客人的
They should tell you that when you check in.
好吧 收到一张照片 看
Oh, boy. Okay, here's a photo, look.
她在打手势
She's using the signal.
什么手势
What signal?
孩子们不能打电话给家长
The kids aren't allowed to call their parents,
但是营地会发照片给我们
but the camp sends out photos,
所以我们约好
so we have a code.
是的 "我们"
Yeah, "We."
竖一根手指表示很好
One finger, she's fine.
两根手指表示不高兴
Two fingers, she's unhappy.
你看 两根手指
Look at this -- two fingers.
我不在手机上看照片
I don't look at pictures on a phone.
要是拍得好 就洗出来放进相册
If it's a good shot, get a print, put it in an album.
这种时候说这个真合适
Interesting time to take a stand.
可看起来她只是
But she looks like she's just doing
在朋友身后比"兔耳朵"
the bunny ears behind her girlfriend.
她就是那样做
Which is exactly what she would do
好骗过大人们 传达秘密信号
to get a secret signal past the authorities.
那是女童军营 不是莱文沃思
Okay, it's a scout camp, not Leavenworth.
她在笑呢 你担心什么啊
She's smiling. What are you worried about?
因为这是她第一次离开家
Because it's her first time away from home. It --
知道吗 也许是这样
You know what? That's probably it.
是我太紧张了 所以...
I'm just -- I'm stressing out, so --
我要去趟办公室
You know, I'm -- I'm gonna go to the office
拿点文件
and pick up some papwork.
我跟你一起走好了
You know what? I'm gonna tag along with you.
你可以把我送到俱乐部
You can drop me off at the club.
我其实不是去办公室
I'm not really going to the office.
随便 我得抽根雪茄
Don't care. Need a cigar.
根据我刚刚的勘查情况
Based off the walk I just took,
侧乳是最新的股沟
side-boob is the new butt crack.
你想去前面吗
So, you want to head down front?
艾丽克斯
Alex!
你得喝了这个
Okay, you need to drink this.
我再去拿一杯
I'll get a new one.
这里有伏特加吗
Uh, is there vodka in here?
如果有的话 它没在发挥什么作用
If there is, it's not doing anybody any good
除非我把它弄到你嘴里
until I get it in there.
米开朗基罗说过如何用大理石
Michelangelo talked about chiseling
凿出美丽的雕像
beautiful sculptures out of marble.
我的凿子是长岛冰茶
Well, my chisel is a long island iced tea,
我用它雕刻出书呆女的狂野一面
and I use it to free the party girl from the block of nerd.
音乐
Music!!
好棒
Yeah!
并非我的所有雕塑都是杰作
Not all my sculptures are masterpieces.
我回来了
I'm ho--
好棒啊
Oh, amazing!
亲爱的 你听见了吗 他很棒有没有
Honey, were you listening? Isn't he good?
-真的很棒 -是啊
- Really good. - Yeah.
真的很棒
Really good.
我还以为你不喜欢班卓琴呢
I -- I thought you didn't like the banjo.
我也以为我不喜欢
I didn't think I did, either,
但他弹得很好
but there's just something about the way he plays.
太悦耳了
It's so... it's so musical.
这是怎么 给老爸的一个惊喜吗
So, what's this, a surprise for old dad?
你偷偷上了几个月的课了吗 也许更久
You been secretly taking lessons for months, probably longer?
没有 我今天才开始摆弄
Nope. I just started messing around with it today.
你学了一整首歌曲
And you learned a whole song.
实际上他学了两首 给他演奏另一首
Actually, he learned two! Play him the other one.
算了 不用了
I'm good, thanks.
那是我的鞋子吗
Are those my shoes?
我在捐赠盒里找到的
I found them in the box of donations.
刚好合脚
They fit him perfectly.
就是有点点紧
If anything, they're a little snug.
他可以踢掉鞋子了
Well, he can kick them off,
因为我们要去跳蹦床了
'cause we are about to do some trampolining.
该去学邓菲翻转了
Time to learn the Dunphy Tuck.
你不是说他可能会受伤吗
I thought you said he could get hurt doing that.
不可能一直保证安全
It's impossible to be safe all the time.
你走进家里都可能受伤呢
You can get hurt just walking into your own house.
我要去把我的戏服挂在
Okay, I'm gonna go hang my costume up
更衣室里 开始暖嗓子了
in my dressing room and start warming up my voice.
更衣室 带我去看看
Dressing room? Ay, show me.
不行 就是男卫生间里的残疾人座位
I can't. It's the handicapped stall in the men's room.
但今晚的重点不是卡梅隆·塔克
But tonight is not about Cameron Tucker.
而是孩子们
It's about the kids.
塔克教练
Coach tucker.
卡普兰先生
Senor Kaplan.
那是什么 穴居人戏服吗
What is that, a caveman costume?
不是 我刚报名演唱
No, I just signed up
《猫》里的《回忆》
to sing "Memory" from "Cats."
不过希望我不是在
Although I hope I'm not on
《油脂》合唱团之后上台
after the "Grease" Chorus.
很难跟他们媲美
They're a tough act to follow.
《回忆》吗
"Memory"?
但那是你要唱的歌
But that is your song.
《回忆》吗 但那是他的歌
"Memory"? But that was his song.
两件猫的戏服
Two cat costumes?
我们不能唱同一首歌
Well, we can't both sing the same song.
那是对才艺秀不尊重
I mean, that would make a mockery of the follies.
我去年演唱过了
Oh, well, I sang last year.
拜托 我坚持 你唱吧
Please, I insist -- you sing.
他放弃了自己的歌
He gave up his song.
去年他就唱的这首歌
That was his song last year.
命运会眷顾他的
Fate will smile upon him.
你愿意为我这样做吗
You would do that for me?
这真是我见过的
This is literally the nicest gesture
最大度的行为
I have ever witnessed --
而我可是从加拿大来的
And I'm from Canada.
我不喜欢这样
I don't like this.
这就像是罗萨尔芭和玛莉索
This is just like when Rosalba and Marisol
发现她们嫁给了同一个男人
found out that they were married to the same man.
玛莉索让步了
Marisol backed down,
结果两天后她死了
but she was found dead two days later.
歌洛莉亚 我觉得你可能
Okay, Gloria, I think there's a chance
是在把一件很正常的事
you're trying to turn a very normal situation
变成了你的肥皂剧
into one of your soap operas.
好吧 但是想想看
Okay, but imagine --
观众对你起立欢呼会让他崩溃的
A standing ovation for you will crush him!
知道吗
You know what?
如果我顾全大局
I'll only look better
会让我的形象更加伟大
if I take the high road --
在后台帮帮忙 让他享受他的时刻
You know, help out backstage, let him have his moment.
天啊
Oh, my goodness!
你即将看到的动作是我的曾曾曾祖父
The move you're about to see was first developed
拉兹万·邓菲发明的
by my great-great-great- grandfather Razvan Dunphy,
但说真的
but, really,
这和人类对飞行的探索一样历史悠久
it's as old as man's quest to fly.
只是转体空翻 对吧
It's just a flip with a twist, right?
还有更多的动作
There's a lot more going on,
但你第一次看见
but you won't be able to absorb it
是无法全部吸收的
the first time you see it.
一 二 三
Eins...zwei...drei--
不行了 不行了
No good. Okay.
你是对的 我没能吸收
You were right. I totally missed it.
我很高兴刚才没弄成 真的
I'm glad that happened. I'm actually glad that happened.
提醒了我邓菲翻转要充满敬意才能完成
It's a good reminder, the Dunphy Tuck demands respect.
这次 我是 来
This...time...for...
真的
real!
吉姆·麦凯 好疼[运动节目主持人]
Jim McKay, that hurts!
我要调整一下这些弹簧
I'm gonna... just adjust these springs.
我觉得挺好啊
They feel fine to me.
你当然觉得好了
I'm sure they do.
你还没有培养出足够敏锐的脚感
You don't have the foot sensitivity of a tramp champ.
如果让我读盲文 我...
If I ever had to read braille, I'd--
天呐 我觉得我做到了
Oh, my God! I think I did it!
我成功了吗
Did I do it?
差不多吧
Almost. Yeah.
你的姿势差了那么点
Your, your form was a little off.
真的吗 但我觉得很棒 再来一次
Really? It felt perfect. I'll try one more time.
我觉得还是不了吧
I'm not sure that's such a good idea.
你可能会沾上 坏习惯
You might cement in some bad...habits.
我又成功了
I did it again!
我去给你倒杯水
I'm gonna get you some water.
你看起来有点不清醒
You seem lightheaded and delusional.
又一次
Again!
亲爱的 你看起来很累
Oh, honey. You look exhausted.
不累 我还是一如既往的威猛
Well, I am not. I am as strong as ever.
我是家里最威猛的人
Certainly the strongest person in the house.
卢克是在做邓菲翻转吗
Is Luke doing the Dunphy Tuck?
学了个百分之六七十吧
Sort of a poor man's version of it.
他加了一个全新的动作
He added a whole new twist.
他这是转多了 好好看看
It's called over-rotation. Look into it.
我当时忙着做扫除
I was so caught up in my spring cleaning,
过了好一阵才发现原来菲尔觉得不自信了
it took me a while to see that Phil was feeling inadequate.
我知道我需要做什么
I knew what I needed to do.
等你们弄完了
When you guys are done out there,
你能把这张清单拿给卢克吗
do you think you could give Luke my list?
这上面有些体力活要干
I have some chores on here that require some muscle.
也许该让我来
Maybe I should take care of that.
我能处理好
No, no, I-I-I can handle it.
卢克正忙着不用脚尖起跳呢
Luke's pretty busy out there not pointing his toes.
他对我说"去找点事做吧"[找一条命]
So he's all like, "Get a life,"
我回他"不了谢谢 我有九条命呢"
and I'm like, "No, thanks. Got nine."
因为我是
I mean, cause...
抱歉打扰了 我画完休息一下
Sorry to interrupt, but I just took a break from painting.
想着过来给你送点喝的
Wanted to come over, bring you some tea
顺便祝你表演成功[摔断一只爪子]
and tell you to break a paw.
他差点就被砸破头了
He almost broke his head.
我知道 非常抱歉
Yes, I know, and I feel horrible about that.
我希望你明白
I-I hope you know
我绝不是有意伤害...
I would never intentionally do anything to harm--
我的喉咙
My throat!
好痛啊
It burns!
他把茶弄得太烫了
He made the tea too hot!
我不是故意的
Not on purpose!
他被塔克教练的喷漆罐绊倒了
He tripped on one of Coach Tucker's paint cans.
我都不记得有把罐子放在那
I don't remember leaving that there!
看看我 我这样可上不了台
Oh, look at me. I can't command a stage.
你来接替我
You, you have to take my place.
我们可以把你推上台
We'll wheel you out onto stage.
这可不行 我们都知道
Oh, come on, we both know
这首歌需要很多拟猫的动作
this song requires catlike movements.
快来人给他换装 画脸
Someone get this man into fur and makeup!
-你在干什么 -清单上最后一项
- What are you doing?! - Last item on the list--
-移桌子 -不 你不应该一个人弄
- move the table. - No. You should not be doing that alone.
真的吗 我已经独自把冰箱搬到路边了
Really? Cause I got the fridge out to the curb.
-怎么做到的 -给它下药
- How? - Drug it.
退后 我要背她起来了
Stand back. I'm turtling her.
不行 你会受伤的 亲爱的
No, you're gonna get hurt, sweetie.
-我去找卢克来 卢克 -不用
- Let me get Luke. Luke! - No, no, no!
我不需要他的帮忙
I don't need his help!
让他去弹那宝贵的班卓琴吧
Let him play his precious Banjo!
感觉连班卓琴都在嘲笑我
It was like the Banjo was mocking me.
*你不似从前英勇*
*You are not the man you used to be*
*每晚起夜四次*
*You get up four times at night to pee*
*噜啦啦噜啦啦噜啦噜啦噜*
*Ba-da-dum ba bat da doot doot doo*
*你已垂垂老去*
*You're super-duper old now*
休息一下吧[爵士名曲]
Take Five.
我不会弹那首歌
I don't know that one.
给我几分钟 我能学会
Give me a couple minutes. I'll figure it out.
这么多噪音 我很难集中精力干活
It's a little hard to get things done with all the noise.
那是什么
What's that?
没什么
Nothing.
那是件
Is that...
胸罩吗
a bra?
你不该带女生来家里的
You're not supposed to have girls up here.
我能解释
I can explain.
不必解释
You don't have to!
你以为自己是个成年人 但你不是
You think you're an adult, but you're not.
你只是住在我屋檐下的小屁孩
You're a kid living under my roof,
你要遵从我的规定
and you have to obey my rules!
G弦断了[丁字裤断了]
The "G" string snapped!
估计不是第一次在这里发生了
Probably not the first time that's happened in here.
不 它打到我眼睛了
No! It hit my eye!
我眼睛流血了吗
Is it bleeding?
首先 眼睛是不会流血的 所以
First of all, eyes can't bleed, so--
小萨米·戴维斯 真是够糟的[艺人 曾出车祸]
Sammy Davis Jr., that's bad!
艾丽克斯
Alex!
我在找我妹妹
I'm looking for my sister.
她留着棕头发
She has brown hair,
打扮得像个书呆子 但不是为了讽刺
dressed like a nerd, but not ironically.
等一下
Hang on!
喂
Hello?
海莉 你和艾丽克斯在一起吗
Haley, are you with Alex?
她不接电话
She's not answering her phone.
这个嘛
Uh, yeah, yeah.
我们现在不在一块儿
We're just a tiny bit separated right now,
但她举止有点怪
but, uh, she's been acting a little strange.
天呐 你什么意思
Oh, no. What do you mean?
她就是有点...
Um, I -- well, I-I'd say she's been, um...
有点不爱搭理人
a bit distant.
不是吧
Oh, no.
妈 别慌
Mom, don't freak out.
没 你们今早出门的时候
No, I was worried about this
我就有点担心了
when you two left this morning.
好吧 她就是有点放不开
Oh, okay, so she was being a little uptight.
开机啊 你个蠢东西[快告诉我]
Come on! Open up, you stupid thing!
好吧 她很扫兴
Okay, fine! She was a total buzzkill, okay!
我就想让她放松点
I just wanted to relax her.
该死
Damn it.
我知道我做错了
I know, I know -- it was a mistake.
但我又没逼她喝
But it's not like I poured it down her throat!
哈佛没录取她
She didn't get into Harvard.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god!
所以她才那么不正常
That's why she's been acting so weird.
等等 你说
Wait. What do you mean,
你没逼她喝是什么意思
you didn't pour it down her throat?
你把她灌醉了吗
Did you get her drunk?
你黑了她的电脑
Hey, you hacked her computer!
那是她吗
Is that her?
我找到她了
Uh, I just found her.
我让她打给你
I'll have her call you.
把我运到我妹妹那儿
Take me to my sister!
莉莉的营地就在树丛后面
All right, Lily's camp is just through those trees.
-我一会就回来 -别着急
- I'll be back soon. - Take your time.
我带着雪茄呢 不寂寞
I got a couple of Robustos to keep me company.
那身衣裳是怎么回事
Um, what's up with the outfit?
身上不会沾味道
It's to keep the smoke off me
歌洛莉亚就不会发现了
so Gloria won't smell it.
你疯了吧
That's insane.
是啊 我失心疯
Yep, I've lost my mind.
祝你顺利把女儿劫出营地
Have fun breaking your daughter out of sleepaway camp.
你当然不会理解
Oh, of course you wouldn't understand.
为什么
Why?
你忘啦
You forgot?
我忘了我不该问为什么
I forgot I shouldn't ask "Why" to things.
当时我九岁 在营地
I was 9 years old, at camp.
那里到处都是蚊子 厕所是露天的
There were mosquitos, compost toilets,
还有恶霸
mean kids.
那是个歌剧露营吧
It was theater camp, wasn't it?
你当然记得那个了
Naturally, you remember that part.
关键是 我恨死露营了
The point is, I hated it.
我又冷又怕
I was -- I was cold, and I was scared,
特别是
especially
有个小孩讲了个特恐怖的鬼故事
after this kid told this terrifying ghost story,
于是我跑出来找到一个公共电话
so I snuck away to a pay phone,
哭着打给你
I called you, crying,
而你的表现比托德·詹森
and in a performance even more predictable
在《狡猾郎中》里的表演更容易被猜透
than Todd Jansen's Artful Dodger,
你不接我回家
you refused to pick me up.
那是为了你好
For your own good.
学会保护自己
Learning to fend for yourself
是成为一个男人的重要一步
is an important part of becoming a man.
在你说我所有的职业成功
Before you claim that all my professional success
都得益于你当年狠心地决定
stems from your very, very brave decision
留在家里沙发上
to stay at home on the couch
看《无敌女金刚》之前
watching "The Bionic Woman,"
我要去接莉莉了
I am going to go get Lily.
这样她才知道她可以一直依靠我
So that she knows she can always count on me.
就这样吧
It's fine.
如果你觉得戏剧性退场是这样
If that's your idea of a dramatic exit,
怪不得托德·詹森拿到了那个角色
it's no wonder Todd Jansen got that part.
一会儿医生就帮你看了
So, the doctor will see you in a few minutes.
还好有人能看得见
Nice someone can see.
你没事的那只眼睛还能瞪人 不错
Glad to know your good eye can still roll.
你还在生气啊
So, still angry, huh?
天呐 我怎么会生气呢
Gee, why would I be angry?
你不过是侮辱了我 把我搞残废
Because you insulted me, maimed me, and belittled
贬低了我在班卓琴和跳床上取得的成就
my achievements in the banjonic and trampolinic arts?
我知道 抱歉
I know. I'm sorry.
我今天的行为很不光彩
I'm not proud of my behavior today.
可能是因为昨天跑了五公里吧
Probably started with the 5K I ran yesterday.
十公里
10K.
其他人跑了十公里
For everyone else.
这是15年来第一次我没跑完
It was the first time in 15 years I couldn't finish.
今天 我能做的事 你做得都比我好
Then, today, it's everything I can do, you can do better.
我不能
No, I can't.
你当然能
Yes, you can.
没关系 又不是你的错
It's okay. It's not your fault.
每个老爸都会经历这一天
Every dad goes through it --
看着儿子蜕变成男子汉的一天
The day he starts seeing his son as a man and not a boy.
这很令人震惊
It's a shock.
就像刚买了高清电视那会儿
Like when we first got high-def TV
发现电视上埃德·布拉德利戴着耳环
and I realized Ed Bradley had an earring.
我没有你想得那么威武雄壮
I'm not as much of a man as you think, dad.
真的吗
Oh, really?
那为什么一个小时前
How come an hour ago,
我手里有个16岁女孩的胸罩
I had a 16-year-old girl's bra in my hand?
能去个私密点的地方谈吗
Can we talk somewhere more private?
那胸罩是我的
The bra belongs to me.
好吧
Oh...kay.
我没想到要跟你谈这个
That's not the conversation I thought we'd be having,
但如果你需要这种外在的东西
but...if that's what you need on the outside
来找到内心真正的自我
to feel like the luke you are on the inside --
不是这样
No!
那是训练道具
It's to practice on.
我不会解胸罩
I stink at unhooking them.
上周 我试过在派对上
Last week, I tried to
解开一个女孩的胸罩
take one off a girl at a party.
我半天都没解开 她就开始笑我
I fumbled for so long, she started to laugh.
到现在我都无法释怀
It still haunts me.
所以这周我才没出去
That's why I didn't go away this week.
我的活动没被取消
My trip wasn't canceled.
后来大家都知道了...
Everyone found out and...
我懂了 你没法面对他们
I get it -- you couldn't face them.
听我说 我知道你人生的这部分
Listen, I know this part of your life
可能前进得比你期望的要慢
may not be moving fast enough for you,
但趁年轻时好好享受吧
but enjoy it while it lasts.
有一天 岁月会快得让你措手不及
Someday, your life's gonna be moving faster than you want,
然后你可能很紧张 结果做了蠢事
and you could wind up doing something dumb,
比如弄瞎你儿子的眼睛
like blinding your son.
我瞎了吗
I'm blind?!
可能不会
Probably not.
卢克·邓菲
Luke Dunphy?
我知道我的年龄不太适合来这里了
I know I'm getting a little old for this place, but...
不过我还是喜欢来这
I do like coming here.
小卢克
Oh, Lukey!
你伤到眼睛了
You hurt your eye.
要抱抱吗
Do you need a hug?
抱紧点
A big one.
来吧
Come here.
艾丽克斯 停下
Alex! Alex, stop!
我追了你快一个小时了
I have been chasing you for, like, an hour!
你要去哪里
Where are you going?!
这个叫伟泽的人说
This guy Weasel said he knows
他知道山里有处温泉
of some hot springs in the hills.
我们正打算去找
We were just gonna go try and find them.
好吧 那我们就十年后见
Oh, okay. So, we'll see you in, like, what, 10 years,
等你用勺子挖条地道
when you spoon-tunnel
从伟泽的地窖里逃出来的时候
your way out of Weasel's basement?
我知道哈佛大学的事了
I know about Harvard.
怎么知道的
How?
妈妈在你电脑上看到的
Mom saw on your computer.
她当然会告诉你了
And of course she told you,
因为她根本不把隐私当回事
because privacy doesn't mean anything.
为什么还要做正确的事呢
Why do things the right way?
-艾丽克斯 我 -不 为了什么
- Alex, I r-- - No! What's the point?
十年成绩全优
Get straight A's for 10 years,
暑假去盖房子
spend your summers building houses,
每天拖着大提琴去上学
drag your cello to school every day,
写完美的论文 都为了什么
write the perfect essay, and for what?!
"不 谢谢 艾丽克斯"
"No, thank you, Alex!"
"我们不想录取你 艾丽克斯"
"We don't want you, Alex!"
好了 注意你的人比注意那个
Okay, you are drawing more attention to yourself
拿雪貂当围巾的人还多
than the guy wearing a ferret as a scarf.
我不在乎了
I don't care anymore!
从小到大我都试图做到完美
I've spent my entire life trying to be perfect,
结果得到什么了
and where did it get me?
我和六千个傻子在这片空地上
I am in a field with 6,000 idiots!
知道吗 我认为这对你来说是件好事
Know what? I think that this is a good thing for you.
-今天能不能别烦我 -不能
- Can you just spare me today? - No.
你一定会考上其中一所
You're obviously going to get into
傲慢自大的学校的
one of those snooty schools,
偶尔你可能会考第二名
and sometimes you're gonna come in second...
或第四名 甚至第十名
or fourth, or maybe even tenth.
但你会振作精神
But you're gonna dust yourself off,
也许涂点唇膏 继续向前走
maybe put on some lipstick for once, and keep going.
我可以为此而难过 好吗
I'm allowed to feel bad about this, okay?
你就是个超级明星
Look, you are a superstar!
从你十岁大我就一直说
I've been saying since you were 10
你以后会站在最高法院里
you're gonna be on the Supreme Court.
谢谢
Thanks.
不过声明一下 我会成为一名科学家
But for the record, I'm gonna be a scientist.
实验服还是法官袍
Lab coat, robe --
只要能盖住你的衣服就行
as long as something's covering up your outfit,
你会没事的
you're gonna be just fine.
我 不想谈这个
I...don't want to talk about it.
我曾在三场业余演出 两场同志婚礼
I had killed with that song at three amateur productions,
和被延误的航班上完美地表演过那首歌
two gay weddings, and a two-hour gate hold on a 747,
但我能看出今天的观众们觉得
but I could tell the audience thought
我为了上台 对卡普兰先生使坏
that I had sabotaged Kaplan to grab the spotlight,
而我的自信卡在喉咙里
and my confidence caught in my throat
就像玩了三天的毛球
like a three-day furball.
我的表演臭到家了
I couldn't have stunk up the place worse
臭过在猫砂盆里唱
if I'd performed in a litter box.
谢谢 谢谢你们
Thank you. Thank you very much.
太棒了 卡梅隆
Bravo, Cameron.
不说了 我回我的单间去了
Can't talk! I'll be in my stall!
现在大家都会讨厌卡梅隆了
So, now everybody hates Cameron.
好吧 我唱不了《回忆》
Okay, look, I can't sing "Memory."
对我来说太难了
It's too much song for me.
所以当我发现塔克教练
So when I found out that coach Tucker
想唱那首歌 我找到了借口
wanted to sing it, as well, I had my out --
谁知他很高尚地让给我
until he nobly stepped aside.
幸运的是 沙袋掉了 大家都怪他
Luckily, the sandbag fell, everyone blamed him,
我知道机会来了
and I just saw my opening.
是我把喷漆罐放在地上
I put the paint cans on the floor
又假装被那杯茶烫到
and pretended that the tea scalded me.
但看到他在台上玉石俱焚的样子
But to see him crash and burn on stage, that...
真是没什么比这更精彩了
It doesn't get better than that.
很快就有了
Oh, it's about to,
因为我把你的麦克打开了
because I turned your microphone on,
外面所有人都听见了
and everybody there is listening
你刚刚说的每句话
to everything that you just said!
不是吧 不不不不
No. No! No, no, no, no, no, no.
你这个禽兽
You monster!
太精彩了 还没有广告
Amazing! And with no commercials!
身处森林最坏的事
The worst thing about the woods
就是你永远不知道会遇到什么
is you never know what you're gonna run into --
一只熊 一个不喜欢城里人的猎人
a bear, a hunter who doesn't take kindly to city folk,
更糟的是...
or worse...
我等不及了 我超爱吃烤棉花糖
I can't wait. I love S'mores.
看到你的女儿比任何时候都开心
...your daughter, as happy as you've ever seen her.
唯一能做的事就是偷偷溜回车里
The only thing to do was to sneak back to the car
想想该编什么谎话骗我爸
and think of a lie to tell my dad along the way.
那是什么
What was that?
我也不知道 我们赶快用铲子拍死它
I don't know, but let's hit it with a shovel.
再用棉花糖棒捅死它
And stab it with our marshmallow sticks!
别别别 我是莉莉的爸爸
No! No, no, no, no! I-I'm Lily's dad.
我是莉莉的...她是我女儿
I'm Lily-- hi. She's mine.
你到这儿来干什么
what are you doing here?
我以为你给我发了求救信号
Okay, I-I thought you gave me the signal.
没有 走开啦
No! Go away.
你让我在一群8岁小孩面前丢脸了
You're embarrassing me in front of 8-year-olds.
抱歉
Sorry.
我刚给这些孩子们讲了个鬼故事
I just finished telling the girls a ghost story.
吓死人了
It was so scary.
你知道什么鬼故事吗
Do you know any?
我知道一个 是我当年露营时听到的
I do know one from my own camp days,
但对你们而言可能太过吓人了
but it's probably too scary for you, s--
-快跟我们说说 -好吧 好吧
- Tell us now! - Okay, okay.
真的很吓人 可别说我没警告过你们
It's really scary. Don't say I didn't warn you.
这故事最好真的精彩
This better be good.
故事也发生在一个营地里 跟这里很像
I-it takes place at a camp a lot like this one,
在森林那边 有一个黑湖
Where just beyond the woods, there was a black lake.
在湖那边 有一个监狱
And just beyond the lake, there was a prison.
一点都不吓人啊
This isn't scary.
好吧 那是个闹鬼的...
Okay, it was a haunted pr--
那是个闹鬼的监狱
It was a haunted prison.
有一天晚上 也就是满月之夜
Now, on this one night, the night of the full moon,
他们称之为"血月"
What they call "The blood moon"...
那个监狱里 有一个鬼
Okay, what was at this prison was a -- was a ghost --
是个老人死后变成的鬼 眼睛闪着红光
The ghost of an old man with glowing red eyes,
可以喷火
Who breathed fire!
好无聊 我们能提前回去睡觉了吗
I'm bored. Can we go to sleep early?
我觉得你忘了今天是血月之夜吧
I think you're forgetting about the blood moon.
那是什么
What's that?!
闪着红光的眼睛
Glowing eyes!
是鬼啊
It's the ghost!
鬼来啦 不要啊
It's the ghost! No!
姑娘们
Girls!
谢你了啊 现在她们应该会好好睡觉了
Thanks for that. Bedtime should be a treat.
看来你终于来营地救了我一次啊
Well, I guess you finally rescued me at camp.
就算迟了 有也胜过无
Better late than never.
顺便说下 我当年的确
By the way, I should've
该去营地把你接回家的
come by and picked you up from camp.
要小孩独立自强那一套
That, uh, "Tough it out" stuff --
都是从我爸那里学来的
That was my dad talking.
他曾经把我丢进一个我很害怕的湖里
He threw me in a lake once I was afraid of.
我跟你说过那事吗
Did I ever tell you about that story?
是的 我们都听过那个故事
Yeah, yeah, we've all heard that story.
你也别太自责了
Now, don't feel too bad.
我完全会错了莉莉的意思
I was completely wrong about Lily.
我差点让她没有享受到
I almost rescued her from
她这辈子最快乐的时光
having the time of her life.
有时候事情就是这样的
Oh, that's the way of things.
一切都自有结果 有一天
Things work out, and someday,
你也会看到她
you'll be able to see her
对她自己的孩子 也产生完全错误的理解
be completely wrong about her kids.
其实挺好玩的
It's fun.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
你想抽根雪茄吗
Want a cigar?
不了 谢谢
No. No, thank you.
我小时候曾偷过一根雪茄抽
You know, I -- I once stole one of those when I was a kid.
抽的我晕乎乎的
Made me completely dizzy.
我都不记得当晚后来发生的事了
I don't remember the rest of the night.
你接下来不是要去观看教职员才艺秀吗
Aren't you going to that faculty follies after this?
没错 那快给我一根
Yeah. Give me one of those.
我以为这里有一层台阶呢
I thought there was a step there.
等你把绷带拆除了
Oh, yeah, you'll get your depth perception back
深度知觉就会回来了
once you get the bandages off.
楼梯中间当心点
Careful in the middle, there.
我还没来得及修...
I still haven't a chance to --
我知道的
I know.
我以为是艾丽克斯回来了呢
I thought you were Alex.
她没有被录取
She didn't get in.
不要啊
Oh, no!
愚蠢的哈佛大学
Stupid Harvard.
"Stupid Harvard"?
她也没被普林斯顿大学录取吗
She didn't get into Princeton, either?
不是啦 只被哈佛拒了
No, just Harvard.
我觉得这个有助于缓解那事对她的打击
I thought that this might soften the blow.
我还做了她最爱吃的菜
And I made her her favorite dinner.
你真是个好妈妈
You're such a good mom.
她回来啦
There she is!
嗨 我都听说了
Hi. I heard.
我真的很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
谢了 妈
Uh, thanks, mom,
但海莉已经让我心里舒坦多了
but Haley already made me feel a little better about it.
我现在不想说话
I just don't really feel like talking right now.
我只想去修改下密码 然后就睡觉
I kind of just want to change my password and get into bed.
好吧
Okay.
她只是需要点时间去淡然接受这事
She just needs a little bit of time to work through it.
独自吗
Alone?
孩子们都长大了
The kids are growing up.
看来他们已经不那么需要我们了
Guess they don't need us as much anymore.
原本就该是这样才对啊
Oh, well, that was the plan.
我只是当初以为
I just thought
我们不会这么失落难受
it would feel better than this.
我也是
Me too.
至少我们还需要彼此
At least we still need each other.
我真的好幸运
And I get so lucky.
行了
Ok.
泡妞绝技宝刀未老
Still got it!